                <ChangeRequest class="oracle.dbtools.crest.model.ChangeRequest" name="[Asset Sec] Asset Securitisation identifiers" id="17478-177">
                    <createdBy>ostarij</createdBy>
                    <comment>
# Overview
Securitisation identifier needs to be reported to ESMA

The Unique identifier to be reported in the ESMA data sets is regulated by Article 11 of EU 2020/1224 (“RTS specifying the information and the details of a securitisation to be made available by the originator, sponsor and SSPE”).

“Article 11 Unique identifiers 1. Each securitisation shall be assigned a unique identifier composed of the following elements, in sequential order: (a) the Legal Entity Identifier of the reporting entity; (b) the letter ‘A’ where the securitisation is an ABCP securitisation or the letter ‘N’ where the securitisation is a non-ABCP securitisation; (c) the four-digit year corresponding to: (i) the year in which the first securities of the securitisation were issued, where the securitisation is a non-ABCP securitisation; (ii) the year in which the first securities within the ABCP programme were issued, where the securitisation is an ABCP securitisation; (d) the number 01 or, where there is more than one securitisation with the same identifier as referred to in points (a), (b) and (c), a two-digit sequential number corresponding to the order in which information about each securitisation is made available. The order of simultaneous securitisations shall be discretionary.”

This identifier, which I refer to as the “ESMA identifier” is therefore different from the identifiers given by EDW or SecRep (the other accredited repository).

Example: BNP Paribas Bas Master Issuer N.V securitisation has EDW ID = `RMBMBE000095100120084` and ESMA ID = `KGCEPHLVVKVRZYO1T647N200801`.

### Contact person
@Arjan.Bos @Olivia.Hauet 

### Business definition
The Unique identifier to be reported in the ESMA securitisation templates is regulated by Article 11 of EU 2020/1224 (“RTS specifying the information and the details of a securitisation to be made available by the originator, sponsor and SSPE”).



### Legal definition
“Article 11 Unique identifiers 1. Each securitisation shall be assigned a unique identifier composed of the following elements, in sequential order: (a) the Legal Entity Identifier of the reporting entity; (b) the letter ‘A’ where the securitisation is an ABCP securitisation or the letter ‘N’ where the securitisation is a non-ABCP securitisation; (c) the four-digit year corresponding to: (i) the year in which the first securities of the securitisation were issued, where the securitisation is a non-ABCP securitisation; (ii) the year in which the first securities within the ABCP programme were issued, where the securitisation is an ABCP securitisation; (d) the number 01 or, where there is more than one securitisation with the same identifier as referred to in points (a), (b) and (c), a two-digit sequential number corresponding to the order in which information about each securitisation is made available. The order of simultaneous securitisations shall be discretionary.”


### Reason for inclusion
Additional attribute to the IReF would give the possibility to connect IReF and ESMA data for public securitisations

The same attribute, or different attributes could be used for Covered bond programmes (requirement by DG-M) and NPL transfers.

In case of several transactions applying to the same instrument, could the attribute contain several identifiers?


### Relationships
_[Related objects]_

### Relevant Framework/Template
The Unique identifier to be reported in the ESMA data sets is regulated by Article 11 of EU 2020/1224 (“RTS specifying the information and the details of a securitisation to be made available by the originator, sponsor and SSPE”).

### Additional documentation/links (optional)
_[Additional info]_

### Before closing checklist
- [ ] Assignee for review
- [ ] Assignee to close
- [ ] Other actions</comment>
                    <notes>https://gitlab.sofa.dev/sdd-bird-team/bird-logical-data-model/-/issues/177</notes>
                    <ownerDesignName>BIRD data models</ownerDesignName>
                    <engineerTo>
                        <item key="9F71AC75-C64B-3A4F-AE9B-7E0028CEC114" value="true"/>
                        <item key="AEFDAE93-361A-74FC-D9B0-896822C5F2BB" value="true"/>
                        <item key="963C5E00-5517-19DF-A89B-FDB8671036FF" value="true"/>
                        <item key="24FC9E45-18D3-C550-6BAD-4693BE2883E4" value="true"/>
                        <item key="48078BB1-66DB-629F-6B3D-FE6F84461BCA" value="true"/>
                        <item key="6BCEF519-13E1-B08A-2794-C031B6E1ADA6" value="true"/>
                    </engineerTo>
                    <status>proposed</status>
                </ChangeRequest>
