                <ChangeRequest class="oracle.dbtools.crest.model.ChangeRequest" name="[SHS] Cumulative recoveries since default for bonds is missing" id="21833-400">
                    <createdBy>ostarij</createdBy>
                    <comment>&lt;!-- See: documentation on [Issues in GitLab](https://gitlab.sofa.dev/sdd-bird-team/bird-logical-data-model/-/wikis/Issues-in-GitLab) --&gt;

### Overview
Cumulative recoveries since default for bonds is missing. 


### Contact person
@Arjan.Bos , @sdressler 

### Description of change request
Debt securities do not have the cumulative recoveries since default in them in the LDM. The issue is to find out if that is needed and how to model them.

### Legal definition
Needed for SHS in Point 5.3.14 in [Guidance notes to reporting agents on SHS regulation](https://www.ecb.europa.eu/pub/pdf/other/ecb.guidance_notes_to_reporting_agents_on_shs_regulation202005\~f7bce14823.en.pdf)

#### Description
Total amount recovered since the date of default.

#### Additional clarifications
This attribute may not be required for the reporting of intra-group holdings (prudential
scope), holdings not recognised on the balance sheet and “pure” short positions
(i.e. those where no positive amount is held and recorded on the asset side), subject
to the discretion of NCBs.

If in accordance with the accounting classification or in the case of equity and
investment fund shares or units the attribute is not applicable, it should not be filled.

The attribute informs about the amount of recoveries received in relation to defaulted
instruments from the start of the latest default of the instrument till the reporting
reference date. It should be clarified that the term “default” in the definition of the data attribute refers to default as specified in Article 178 of the CRR.

If an instrument is in default at the reporting reference date, then an amount of
recoveries received in the period since the start of the default must be reported. If no
recoveries have been received since the start of the default, zero must be reported.

It should be noted that the amounts of recoveries since default are not accumulated
over multiple defaults of one and the same instrument (i.e. where an instrument
defaults, cures and re-defaults again). Accordingly, there is no carrying-over of
recoveries from one default to another place – every time a new default starts, the
cumulative recoveries since default are set to zero and the accumulation starts anew.

Where the reason for default is other than past due, the amounts recovered must also
be reported in this attribute.

For the purpose of calculating the cumulative recoveries after default, all recoveries
should be taken into account irrespective of their source; for example, the attribute
must consider any voluntary cash repayments, any proceeds from liquidating of
collateral, amounts received as a result of calling guarantees, etc. Moreover,
recoveries from any protection securing the instrument must be included in this
attribute.

However, the attribute should be reported net of any recovery costs – for example, if a
cost is incurred when realising proceeds from a collateral (e.g. liquidating a real estate
property which serves as protection), only the proceeds remaining after deduction of
the costs of the liquidation process are reported in this attribute.

In all other cases, where an instrument is no longer in default at a reporting reference
date, the relevant NCB may dispense with the requirement to fill the attribute.

In the case of proportional consolidation of holding entities (see Article 18(4) of the
CRR), the total holding amount has to be adjusted for the reporting, in accordance with
the proportional share of consolidation.

### Summary of impacted LDM objects/attributes
- Debt security
- one of the Debt security position entity types


### Before closing checklist
- [ ] Assignee for review
- [ ] Assignee to close 
- [ ] Any other actions to be taken</comment>
                    <notes>https://gitlab.sofa.dev/sdd-bird-team/bird-logical-data-model/-/issues/400</notes>
                    <ownerDesignName>BIRD data models</ownerDesignName>
                    <engineerTo>
                        <item key="9F71AC75-C64B-3A4F-AE9B-7E0028CEC114" value="true"/>
                        <item key="AEFDAE93-361A-74FC-D9B0-896822C5F2BB" value="true"/>
                        <item key="963C5E00-5517-19DF-A89B-FDB8671036FF" value="true"/>
                        <item key="24FC9E45-18D3-C550-6BAD-4693BE2883E4" value="true"/>
                        <item key="48078BB1-66DB-629F-6B3D-FE6F84461BCA" value="true"/>
                        <item key="6BCEF519-13E1-B08A-2794-C031B6E1ADA6" value="true"/>
                    </engineerTo>
                    <status>proposed</status>
                </ChangeRequest>
