                <ChangeRequest class="oracle.dbtools.crest.model.ChangeRequest" name="AE Requirements - Cover pool amount in excess of minimum coverage requirements" id="26030-470">
                    <createdBy>ostarij</createdBy>
                    <comment># Overview

In template F 35.00.d information about **Cover pool amount in excess of minimum coverage requirements** is required.

In particular this amount is required in the form of:

* **Nominal amount. Excess of min coverage required**
* **Present value (swap)/Market Value. Excess of min coverage required**
* **Asset-specific value. Excess of min coverage required**

### Contact person

@Arianna.Nuvoli, @Maria_Manuel.Henriques, @Pietro.Ferroni

### Business definition

Regulators set minimum coverage requirements to ensure that the value of the cover pool meets or exceeds the value of the covered bonds. The cover pool amount in excess of minimum coverage requirements refers to the additional value of the collateral beyond the required minimum.

### Legal definition

* According to Annex XVII, **Cover pool amount in excess of minimum coverage requirements** is: 

_Amounts of cover pool, including cover pool derivative positions with net positive market values, in excess of requirements of minimum coverage (over-collateralisation)_

* The **Cover pool** is defined in Annex XVII as follows: 

_The cover pool consist of all positions, including cover pool derivative positions, from the perspective of the covered bond issuer, with a net positive market value, that are subject to the respective covered bond protective measures._

* And **as per the relevant statutory covered bond regime:**

_Amounts of over-collateralisation compared with the minimum coverage required by the relevant statutory covered bond regime (_[_Annex VII_](https://eba.europa.eu/sites/default/files/document_library/Publications/Draft%20Technical%20Standards/2020/ITS/ITS%20on%20supervisory%20reporting%20changes%20related%20to%20CRR2%20and%20Backstop%20Regulation/Annexes/886567/Annex%2017%20%28Asset%20encumbrance%29.pdf)_)._

Discussing with the AE subgroup members, this should be basically the difference between what reported in F 35.00 c020+c080 and c150+c220, i.e. the difference between the amount of the liabilities and the amount of the cover pool of assets. However since the calculation of the amounts is not fixed and there no EBA VRs we can't use a derivation.

* And **As per credit rating agencies’ methodology to maintain current external credit rating on covered bond:**

_Amounts of over-collateralisation compared with the level that, according to information on the respective credit rating agency's methodology available to the covered bond issuer, would at a minimum be required to support the existing credit rating issued by the respective credit rating agency (Annex XVII)._

### Reason for inclusion

AE Integration

### Relationships

_\[Related objects\]_

### Relevant Framework/Template

AE F 35.00.d

### Additional documentation/links (optional)

_\[Additional info\]_

### Before closing checklist

- [ ] Assignee for review
- [ ] Assignee to close
- [ ] Other actions</comment>
                    <notes>https://gitlab.sofa.dev/sdd-bird-team/bird-logical-data-model/-/issues/470</notes>
                    <ownerDesignName>BIRD data models</ownerDesignName>
                    <engineerTo>
                        <item key="9F71AC75-C64B-3A4F-AE9B-7E0028CEC114" value="true"/>
                        <item key="AEFDAE93-361A-74FC-D9B0-896822C5F2BB" value="true"/>
                        <item key="963C5E00-5517-19DF-A89B-FDB8671036FF" value="true"/>
                        <item key="24FC9E45-18D3-C550-6BAD-4693BE2883E4" value="true"/>
                        <item key="48078BB1-66DB-629F-6B3D-FE6F84461BCA" value="true"/>
                        <item key="6BCEF519-13E1-B08A-2794-C031B6E1ADA6" value="true"/>
                    </engineerTo>
                    <status>implementing</status>
                </ChangeRequest>
