                <ChangeRequest class="oracle.dbtools.crest.model.ChangeRequest" name="AE Requirements - Available for encumbrance - AVLBL_ENCMBRNC" id="26377-479">
                    <createdBy>ostarij</createdBy>
                    <comment>## Overview
AE requires information about the _Availability for encumbrance_ for non-encumbranced assets.

## Contact person
@Arianna.Nuvoli @Maria_Manuel.Henriques @Pietro.Ferroni 

## Business definition
The _Availability for encumbrace indicator_ is needed for all assets that are unencumbered, specifically:
- Collateral received (Loans and advances, debt securities, equities, Derivatives, Immaterial rights, Physical collaterals (real estate, aircraft, ship, property plants and equipment, gold etc.))
- Own debt securities issued (Covered bonds, securitizations, Others).

## Legal definition
Annex 17, section 2.2.1, paragraph 15:
&gt; For the collateral received by the reporting institution and the own debt securities issued other than own covered bonds or securitisations, the category of “non-encumbered” assets is split between those “available for encumbrance” or potentially eligible to be encumbered and those “non-available for encumbrance”.

Annex 17, section 2.2.1, paragraph 16:
&gt; Assets are “non-available for encumbrance” when they have been received as collateral and the reporting institution is not permitted to sell or re-pledge the collateral, except in the case of a default by the owner of the collateral. Own debt securities issued other than own covered bonds or securitisations are non-available for encumbrance when there is any restriction in the terms of the issuance to sell or re-pledge the securities held.

## Reason for inclusion
AE integration

## Relevant Framewrok/Template
- F 32.02.a
- F 32.03.b

## Before closing checklist
* [ ] Assign reviewer (orignal author of the issue)
* [ ] Assignee to close (should not be same as original author)
* [ ] If the issue resolution does not require a logical data model, technical, or code change, a continuous improvement action should have been taken (e.g. improve documentation)</comment>
                    <notes>https://gitlab.sofa.dev/sdd-bird-team/bird-logical-data-model/-/issues/479</notes>
                    <ownerDesignName>BIRD data models</ownerDesignName>
                    <engineerTo>
                        <item key="9F71AC75-C64B-3A4F-AE9B-7E0028CEC114" value="true"/>
                        <item key="AEFDAE93-361A-74FC-D9B0-896822C5F2BB" value="true"/>
                        <item key="963C5E00-5517-19DF-A89B-FDB8671036FF" value="true"/>
                        <item key="24FC9E45-18D3-C550-6BAD-4693BE2883E4" value="true"/>
                        <item key="48078BB1-66DB-629F-6B3D-FE6F84461BCA" value="true"/>
                        <item key="6BCEF519-13E1-B08A-2794-C031B6E1ADA6" value="true"/>
                    </engineerTo>
                    <status>implementing</status>
                </ChangeRequest>
