                <ChangeRequest class="oracle.dbtools.crest.model.ChangeRequest" name="AE Requirements - Encumbered/Not encumbered" id="27083-481">
                    <createdBy>ostarij</createdBy>
                    <comment># Overview

In Asset Encumbrance, it is necessary to identify if something (an asset or a collateral received) is encumbered.

### Contact person

@Arianna.Nuvoli , @Maria_Manuel.Henriques , @Pietro.Ferroni 

### Business definition

**According to Annex XVII:**

_For the purpose of this Annex and Annex XVI an asset shall be treated as encumbered if it has been pledged or if it is subject to any form of arrangement to secure, collateralise or credit enhance any transaction from which it cannot be freely withdrawn._

_It is important to note, that assets pledged that are subject to any restrictions in withdrawal, such as for instance assets that require prior approval before withdrawal or replacement by other assets, should be considered encumbered. The definition is not based on an explicit legal definition, such as title transfer, but rather on economic principles, as the legal frameworks may differ in this respect across countries. The definition is however closely linked to contractual conditions._

_The EBA sees the following types of contracts being well covered by the definition (this is a non-exhaustive list):_

* _secured financing transactions, including repurchase contracts and agreements, securities lending and other forms of secured lending;_
* _various collateral agreements, for instance collateral placed for the market value of derivatives transactions;_
* _financial guarantees that are collateralised. It should be noted, that if there is no impediment to withdrawal of collateral, such as prior approval, for the unused part of guarantee, then only the used amount should be allocated (on a pro-rata allocation);_
* _collateral placed at clearing systems, CCPs and other infrastructure institutions as a condition for access to service. This includes default funds and initial margins;_
* _central bank facilities. Pre-positioned assets should not be considered encumbered, unless the central bank does not allow withdrawal of any assets placed without prior approval. As for unused financial guarantees, the unused part, i.e. above the minimum amount required by the central bank, should be allocated on a pro-rata basis among the assets placed at the central bank;_
* _underlying assets from securitisation structures, where the financial assets have not been de-recognised from the institution’s financial assets. The assets that are underlying retained securities do not count as encumbered, unless these securities are pledged or provided as collateral in any way to secure a transaction;_
* _assets in cover pools used for covered bond issuance. The assets that are underlying covered bonds count as encumbered, except in certain situations where the institution holds the corresponding covered bonds (‘own-issued bonds’);_
* _as a general principle, assets which are being placed at facilities that are not used and can be freely withdrawn should not be considered encumbered._

### Legal definition

_\[Legal reference\]_

### Reason for inclusion

_AE Requirements_

### Relationships

_\[Related objects\]_

### Relevant Framework/Template

_AE F 32.01, 32.02 a/b, 32.03 a/b, 32.04 b, 33.00 a/b, 35.00 a/b/d, 36.01 a/c, 36.02 a/c_

### Additional documentation/links (optional)
_This request seems to be related with the previously opened _[_issue 194_](https://gitlab.sofa.dev/sdd-bird-team/bird-logical-data-model/-/issues/194)_._

### Before closing checklist

- [ ] Assignee for review
- [ ] Assignee to close
- [ ] Other actions</comment>
                    <notes>https://gitlab.sofa.dev/sdd-bird-team/bird-logical-data-model/-/issues/481</notes>
                    <ownerDesignName>BIRD data models</ownerDesignName>
                    <engineerTo>
                        <item key="9F71AC75-C64B-3A4F-AE9B-7E0028CEC114" value="true"/>
                        <item key="AEFDAE93-361A-74FC-D9B0-896822C5F2BB" value="true"/>
                        <item key="963C5E00-5517-19DF-A89B-FDB8671036FF" value="true"/>
                        <item key="24FC9E45-18D3-C550-6BAD-4693BE2883E4" value="true"/>
                        <item key="48078BB1-66DB-629F-6B3D-FE6F84461BCA" value="true"/>
                        <item key="6BCEF519-13E1-B08A-2794-C031B6E1ADA6" value="true"/>
                    </engineerTo>
                    <status>proposed</status>
                </ChangeRequest>
