                <ChangeRequest class="oracle.dbtools.crest.model.ChangeRequest" name="[FINREP] F 44.04 Disclosures of Staff expenses" id="27161-483">
                    <createdBy>ostarij</createdBy>
                    <comment>&lt;!-- See: documentation on [Issues in GitLab](https://gitlab.sofa.dev/sdd-bird-team/bird-logical-data-model/-/wikis/Issues-in-GitLab) --&gt;


# Overview
2021_5793 Disclosures of Staff expenses Management body in its supervisory function in FINREP Template 44.4

In its Q&amp;A, the EBA explicitly requires FINREP disclosure of remuneration/meeting fees under personnel expenses. I assume this is due to the comparability between the individual EU countries, as in many countries there is no separation between the management board and the supervisory board/board of directors, but only one board?? In principle, FINREP requires that this reporting system reflects the accounting. In this case, however, the EBA explicitly requires a certain disclosure, which in my view should be followed. This results in a breakthrough in the uniformity of accounting and FINREP disclosure. 

Is my interpretation correct, that in the interests of uniformity, all reporting scopes for FinRep, shall comply with the EBA Q&amp;A regardless of the scope of reporting. Meaning, also the ones not reporting F 44.4 need to separate these fees? How will that be reflected – you will only notice such cases, if you analyze FullFinRep reporting scope.


### Contact person
@Arjan.Bos @andreamerz 


### Related issues
#482</comment>
                    <notes>https://gitlab.sofa.dev/sdd-bird-team/bird-logical-data-model/-/issues/483</notes>
                    <ownerDesignName>BIRD data models</ownerDesignName>
                    <engineerTo>
                        <item key="9F71AC75-C64B-3A4F-AE9B-7E0028CEC114" value="true"/>
                        <item key="AEFDAE93-361A-74FC-D9B0-896822C5F2BB" value="true"/>
                        <item key="963C5E00-5517-19DF-A89B-FDB8671036FF" value="true"/>
                        <item key="24FC9E45-18D3-C550-6BAD-4693BE2883E4" value="true"/>
                        <item key="48078BB1-66DB-629F-6B3D-FE6F84461BCA" value="true"/>
                        <item key="6BCEF519-13E1-B08A-2794-C031B6E1ADA6" value="true"/>
                    </engineerTo>
                    <status></status>
                </ChangeRequest>
