                <ChangeRequest class="oracle.dbtools.crest.model.ChangeRequest" name="Date of non-performing status versus Date of performing status - why different treatment?" id="36568-527">
                    <createdBy>ostarij</createdBy>
                    <comment>&lt;!-- See: documentation on [Issues in GitLab](https://gitlab.sofa.dev/sdd-bird-team/bird-logical-data-model/-/wikis/Issues-in-GitLab) --&gt;


# Overview
Hi

I struggle a little bit with how the concept of "Performing status" is unaligned in Instrument and Credit facility.
Also, how this correlates with the date field sub optimally.
In the credit facility, I interpret it as it covers a two-way scenario, where it is monitoring the change regardless which "direction"; from non-performing to performing or vice-versa.
In the instrument entity, the date and the related status, is only working in a one-way scenario.
Maybe, the above is just an unfortunate mistake? My suggestion is that Instrument should replicate Credit facility in this matter.
AnaCredit Reporting Manual – Part II – Datasets and data attributes
Find example in table 63.


From the attributes list in framework model BIRD 6.5.
![image](/uploads/12aadb124bec584a681944ffd75ff020/image.png)



### Contact person
_[m.peters80@gmail.com]_

### Business definition
_[Business requirements]_

### Legal definition
Implementing Regulation (EU) No 680/2014.

AnaCredit Reporting Manual
Part II – Datasets and data attributes: Anacredit 5.4.10


### Reason for inclusion
_[Justifications]_

### Relationships
_[Related objects]_

### Relevant Framework/Template
Instruments recognised in the balance sheet in accordance with the accounting
standard are reported with the value used for their classification in FINREP Template
18. For further details regarding the classification as non-performing, refer to Part 2,
paragraphs 213 to 239, of Annex V to the amended ITS.


Definition: The date on which the performing status as reported in “performing status of
the instrument” is considered to have been established or changed.

### Additional documentation/links (optional)
_[Additional info]_

### Before closing checklist
- [ ] Assignee for review
- [ ] Assignee to close
- [ ] Other actions</comment>
                    <notes>https://gitlab.sofa.dev/sdd-bird-team/bird-logical-data-model/-/issues/527</notes>
                    <ownerDesignName>BIRD data models</ownerDesignName>
                    <engineerTo>
                        <item key="9F71AC75-C64B-3A4F-AE9B-7E0028CEC114" value="true"/>
                        <item key="AEFDAE93-361A-74FC-D9B0-896822C5F2BB" value="true"/>
                        <item key="963C5E00-5517-19DF-A89B-FDB8671036FF" value="true"/>
                        <item key="24FC9E45-18D3-C550-6BAD-4693BE2883E4" value="true"/>
                        <item key="48078BB1-66DB-629F-6B3D-FE6F84461BCA" value="true"/>
                        <item key="6BCEF519-13E1-B08A-2794-C031B6E1ADA6" value="true"/>
                    </engineerTo>
                    <status>proposed</status>
                </ChangeRequest>
