                <ChangeRequest class="oracle.dbtools.crest.model.ChangeRequest" name='Using "Derived " as a prefix for attributes in derived data entity types' id="38647-542">
                    <createdBy>ostarij</createdBy>
                    <comment>
&lt;!-- See: documentation on [Issues in GitLab](https://gitlab.sofa.dev/sdd-bird-team/bird-logical-data-model/-/wikis/Issues-in-GitLab) --&gt;

### Overview

In the latest version of the BIRD LDM the prefix "Derived " is used for some attributes in derived data entity types.

From a logical model perspective this prefix is not necessary because derived attributes are located in derived data entity types and are therefore sufficiently identifiable, e.g., is is clear that the attribute `Performing status` in the entity type `Financial asset instrument derived data` is derived. Hence, the prefix should be avoided.

The most likely reason for adding such a prefix is related to implementation concerns. Specifically the fact that, when forward engineering entity types with attributes having the same name / identifier / code into one table this creates a logical conflict - a table must not have two columns with the same name / identifier / code. 

If this is the case it clearly violates the BIRD LDM's design principles, especially 'Principle 1: We separate our concerns', and therefore must be avoided.

### Contact person

dominik.lin-ully@oenb.at

### Description of change request

Remove the prefix "Derived " from attributes in derived data entity types.

### Summary of impacted LDM objects/attributes

* attributes where the prefix "Derived " is used

### Forward Engineering considerations

Merging multiple entity types comprising attributes with the same identifier / code without special treatment will result in logical conflict - one table must not have two columns with the same identifier / code.

Suggestion(s):
1. (on a conceptual level) define the expected behaviour for such situations including implications (especially the translation of the BIRD LDM in SQL data modeler format into the SMCube data model),
2. choose the most appropriate solution and implement it
3. avoid implementation concerns leaking into the BIRD LDM

### Before closing checklist
- [ ] Assignee for review
- [ ] Assignee to close 
- [ ] Any other actions to be taken</comment>
                    <notes>https://gitlab.sofa.dev/sdd-bird-team/bird-logical-data-model/-/issues/542</notes>
                    <ownerDesignName>BIRD data models</ownerDesignName>
                    <engineerTo>
                        <item key="9F71AC75-C64B-3A4F-AE9B-7E0028CEC114" value="true"/>
                        <item key="AEFDAE93-361A-74FC-D9B0-896822C5F2BB" value="true"/>
                        <item key="963C5E00-5517-19DF-A89B-FDB8671036FF" value="true"/>
                        <item key="24FC9E45-18D3-C550-6BAD-4693BE2883E4" value="true"/>
                        <item key="48078BB1-66DB-629F-6B3D-FE6F84461BCA" value="true"/>
                        <item key="6BCEF519-13E1-B08A-2794-C031B6E1ADA6" value="true"/>
                    </engineerTo>
                    <status>proposed</status>
                </ChangeRequest>
